<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: web | authenticgeek]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.nickoneill.name/categories/web/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.nickoneill.name/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-20T14:43:43-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.nickoneill.name/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick O'Neill]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[quo network expansion]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.nickoneill.name/quonetwork/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-29T15:09:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.nickoneill.name/quonetwork</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The quo network is my tongue-in-cheek collection of single-serving sites that started with the html entity &amp;raquo; back when I was at Six Apart. I could never remember the key command to type the right double angle quotes unicode symbol and I ended up searching the term on google endlessly because I used it just infrequently enough to prevent myself from developing any sort of muscle memory for it. The sites I always found were clearly autogenerated from some complete html entity reference and terrible to look at.</p>

<p>Enter <a href="http://raquo.net">raquo.net</a>. I figured that most web developers were in the same boat so I whipped up a quick design for a site that did nothing other than list some ways to access the symbol. Considering the non-existent competition it quickly became the top result for the search term &lsquo;raquo&rsquo; and &ndash; either for humor or utility &ndash; people started linking to it.</p>

<p>I know it lived in some obscurity for a while, I&rsquo;ve owned the domain since January of &lsquo;05 though it doesn&rsquo;t show up on delicious until November of '06 and only 117 times since then. It&rsquo;s a niche destination, for sure. Some might say that a site based on an html entity will always live in internet obscurity.</p>

<p>Sometime afterward I picked up <a href="http://laquo.net">laquo.net</a>, left double angle quotes, and <a href="http://www.fattrash.com">Jamison</a> coined the term &lsquo;the quo network&rsquo; to make a media empire out of a molehill. Later, <a href="http://kottke.org/08/02/single-serving-sites">kottke made a list</a> of &ldquo;single serving&rdquo; sites and someone made <a href="http://www.alistofsites.com">a list of sites</a>. Since then I added two single quote forms, <a href="http://rsaquo.net">rsaquo</a> and <a href="http://lsaquo.net">lsaquo</a> to round out my collection of angle quote domains.</p>

<p>I managed the lot of them in Movable Type for the longest time because it was (at the time) easy place to template a bunch of sites. I squirmed when I had to change something across them all a while back and put it off entirely when I realized the MT database I had used to create them was mothballed and would require setting up a completely new install and import.</p>

<p>Finally, I recently noticed two easy expansion &lsquo;properties&rsquo; recently that were at least equally and probably more useful than raquo, <a href="http://rdquo.net">rdquo</a> and <a href="http://ldquo.net">ldquo</a>, the right and left double quotations. Maybe more functionally known as curly quotes, or pretty quotes (or those god damn microsoft word quotes). Inspired, I thought about how I would manage sites like these ideally and I ended up making a simple templating script in python with mustache and pushing each file out to the right place with rsync. That allowed me to create a couple more sites, the single quote versions <a href="http://rsquo.net">rsquo</a> and <a href="http://lsquo.net">lsquo</a>, with even less effort.</p>

<p>As an aside, the scripts used to create and push these sites are all stored on <a href="http://www.dropbox.com">Dropbox</a> so I can essentially update the sites from any machine that has a Dropbox client and some open source software. You&rsquo;ll probably hear more from me about Dropbox in the near future since my goal is to gain some independence from the device I&rsquo;m currently working on. Ideally I&rsquo;d be able to get a new computer, type my Dropbox password and start working like it was yesterday (yes, I <em>will</em> pay for that convenience).</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve looked around a bit now and I think these two sites are the last to make it into the network. There are no more useful quo entities (the low-9 versions of fancy quotes, sbquo and bdquo are hardly ever used) and the real icing on the cake, quot.net, has been registered for years and is probably unlikely to come up for registration any time soon.</p>

<p>Thus ends the developmental stage of the quo network. I&rsquo;ll continue hosting the quo network as long as it doesn&rsquo;t become a huge burden and, considering it essentially pays for my hosting every year, that shouldn&rsquo;t be any time soon. Enjoy, internet.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
