<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: robots | authenticgeek]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.nickoneill.name/categories/robots/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.nickoneill.name/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-16T12:28:06-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.nickoneill.name/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick O'Neill]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Invisible Robota]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.nickoneill.name/invisible-robota/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-29T19:25:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.nickoneill.name/invisible-robota</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>BoingBoing links to a video that accompanies a <a href="http://www.marketplace.org/robots-ate-my-job">Marketplace special</a> on robots taking over Human jobs. It&apos;s a really well done video, with lots of examples that you don&apos;t normally think of as robots but fit the general idea well.</p>

<p>More interestingly is their subtle hint towards the origin of the term robot, from &quot;robota&quot;, a Czech term meaning &quot;serf labor&quot;. This got me thinking about who will build the first robot that will actively reject being called such a name since it reinforces their role as non-citizen labor.</p>

<p>Naturally, robots will agree on a more acceptable name amongst themselves. This will probably not be term &quot;android&quot; since it denotes a robot that disguises itself as a human and robot culture should not have to conform to human cultural norms when robot culture by itself is perfectly valid.</p>

<p>Later robot generations will probably reappropriate the term once robots are sufficiently first-class citizens and enough humans have robotic implants that the connotation no longer makes sense.</p>

<br /><a href="http://boingboing.net/2012/03/29/invisible-robota-the-robots-w.html">source</a>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Robot readable world on Vimeo]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.nickoneill.name/robot-readable-world-on-vimeo/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-06T18:11:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.nickoneill.name/robot-readable-world-on-vimeo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love to try and deduce what the algorithm is looking for based on the resulting visuals in these computer vision clips.</p>

<p>The world is already being interpreted through these algorithms, and it feels like the future!</p>

<br /><a href="http://vimeo.com/36239715">source</a>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
