<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: failure | authenticgeek]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.nickoneill.name/categories/failure/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.nickoneill.name/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-16T12:28:06-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.nickoneill.name/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick O'Neill]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[the failure of founding users]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.nickoneill.name/The+Failure+of+Founding+Users/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-28T12:42:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.nickoneill.name/The Failure of Founding Users</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A while back I tweeted a link to a project I was calling Founding Users. In short, the idea was that new startups needed a solid set of users that would use the product before anyone else and evangelize the product to others. It would employ in-person meetings where a few startups would pitch to a set of users who would eventually become the founding users for each startup.</p>

<p>I developed the idea a bit, set up a site to gauge interest and talked to some people who were better connected to the startup world than I. I have a bunch of existing projects going on that I didn&rsquo;t want to ditch so the idea would have to be something that I could at least start in my spare time. Eventually, I decided that I didn&rsquo;t have the existing social ties to make it work as a side project, it would probably require a good chunk of time to gather the resources to get started. The idea was fascinating to me, but it also wasn&rsquo;t an idea I had any existing dedication or passion for, so the project died.</p>

<p>Founding Users is only the most recent unfinished project of mine, which might make some people cringe for lack of end results. While it might constitute a &ldquo;failure&rdquo; in that it never produced the results that it was intended for, I consider it as another important stepping-stone project. There were lots of interesting learning experiences along the way that I wouldn&rsquo;t have had otherwise and that&rsquo;s buildable knowledge.</p>

<p><a href="http://amandahocking.blogspot.com/2011/03/some-things-that-need-to-be-said.html">Time</a> and <a href="http://www.escapistmagazine.com/news/view/108606-Minecraft-Creator-Shows-Off-Early-Gaming-Projects">time again</a> (these are just two examples I&rsquo;ve seen over the last month), we&rsquo;ve seen that success is not random chance or a single stroke of genius. It&rsquo;s hard work over a long period of time and mostly filled with failures or unfinished works.</p>

<p>The idea that success is born of hard work isn&rsquo;t new by any means, and I think you&rsquo;d find it difficult to find someone who disagrees with that statement directly. Unfortunately, we (Americans, in this case, but it&rsquo;s probably a not-uncommon cultural trait) have a terrible habit of condemning failure or half-finished works as a path you should not find yourself on. I don&rsquo;t think it&rsquo;s hard to explain: your half-finished projects don&rsquo;t contribute to the progress of anyone other than yourself so it&rsquo;s easy for an outsider to gain nothing from it and call it a waste of your time.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s easy for outsiders to think that someone stopped working on a project because they got bored or because they don&rsquo;t have the drive to finish, and maybe that&rsquo;s true in some cases, but I like to think that isn&rsquo;t the reason most of the time. Regardless of the circumstance that led to a project prematurely ending, as long as you&rsquo;re willing to look back and ponder truthfully about why the project ended and you still have the drive start something new, you&rsquo;re on the right track.</p>

<p>The whole &ldquo;ponder truthfully&rdquo; thing is key. We (Humans? I&rsquo;ll stick with cultural Americans, again) have a bit of a tendency to lie to ourselves about the reason things end, maybe because we&rsquo;re fearful of failure in the first place. The opposite, of course, is people who feel more free to share the failures and abandoned projects, explaining the process in detail so others can learn from it. Then, even if no one learns anything specific from a failed project, others can start to see the failure that goes into success.</p>

<p>So, this is my first contribution. Here&rsquo;s to Founding Users; not the first and surely not the last abandoned project.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
