<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: games | authenticgeek]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.nickoneill.name/categories/games/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.nickoneill.name/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-17T09:41:13-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.nickoneill.name/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick O'Neill]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Return of Blog, Holidays Edition]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.nickoneill.name/return-of-blog/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-22T15:13:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.nickoneill.name/return-of-blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Good day, blog friends!</p>

<p>Not counting <a href="http://blog.nickoneill.name/muniverse-2.html">Muniverse</a> (and I don&rsquo;t, it was waiting to be published for a while), it has been quite a time since I last wrote a thing. Here&rsquo;s some stuff that doesn&rsquo;t warrant its own post:</p>

<p>Brad and I finally finished a remote garage door opener based on an Arduino and WiFly. See the incredible frustration documented on G+ <a href="https://plus.google.com/115863474911002159675/posts/2PSkLbtUJRB">here</a> and <a href="https://plus.google.com/115863474911002159675/posts/WCen2ZJE9vz">here</a>. A few more tweaks and the whole thing will be on github.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m doing some more frequent science tweeting with <a href="https://twitter.com/finestructure">@finestructure</a>. I never realized I felt a little trapped in my regular twitter account, I&rsquo;m not an oversharer and I don&rsquo;t like to innundate my friends with dumb stuff. Strangers, on the other hand, love dumb stuff. Seriously though, it&rsquo;s full of excellent science and snark.</p>

<p>I want to get back to blogging more on the proper Fine Structure blog but I&rsquo;m frustrated with my publishing setup there. I want to adapt <a href="https://github.com/nickoneill/go-publisher">my dropbox static publisher</a> for this purpose but it requires some thinking, generalizing and coding. Maybe during vacation, or after I write some content.</p>

<p>Work continues to be enjoyable. There are many ways to run a small contracting business and my current method involves doing enough directly billable work to be comfortable and then investing the rest of my time in learning new things &ndash; not always directly related to work. I don&rsquo;t think I could ever swing a deal like that at a standard salaried job so I think I&rsquo;ll be doing this for a while.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m spending a bit of time playing <a href="http://www.bay12games.com/dwarves/">Dwarf Fortress</a> (as little time as someone can spend and still improve in the Most Complex Game Ever). I tend to leave it alone for a few weeks then see something that inspires me to start a new fort, play that for a few days and get totally destroyed by a seige of undead. Such is life in the DF. I would very much like to try a Let&rsquo;s Play video for DF so we&rsquo;ll see where that idea goes in the next few weeks.</p>

<p>I started writing about my current reading list here but it ran far too long, that will have to come at a later date. Welcome back, blog!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tiny NES Cartridge Keychains]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.nickoneill.name/tiny-nes-cartridge/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-09T08:16:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.nickoneill.name/tiny-nes-cartridge</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a serious labor of love. Ben Purdy puts together a <a href="http://www.benpurdy.com/2012/07/quarter-scale-nes-cartridges/">scale, keychainable NES cartridge</a> for his band.</p>

<p>Laser cutting and 3D printing were not quite up to the task (cost, materials, etc) so he milled his own in wax using a drill press on a moving stage and then cast it in resin. Old school methods but absolutely awesome results. You must see it to believe it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Valve Handbook]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.nickoneill.name/the-valve-handbook/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-21T17:10:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.nickoneill.name/the-valve-handbook</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I don&rsquo;t often recommend reading company handbooks but the <a href="http://cdn.flamehaus.com/Valve_Handbook_LowRes.pdf">Valve company handbook</a> is definitely an exception.</p>

<p>It feels like a bunch of smart nerds got together and ignored all the management advice they were given from every other boilerplate company. Then they made a bunch of awesome games and didn&rsquo;t compromise on their values. Now they&rsquo;re smart rich nerds.</p>

<p>via <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/rr/status/193741110558990336">@rr</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[0x10c]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.nickoneill.name/0x10c-from-notch/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-04T08:27:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.nickoneill.name/0x10c-from-notch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The creator of Minecraft has released the basics around his new game, <a href="http://0x10c.com/">0x10<sup>c</sup></a>. It&rsquo;s scifi-ish, based around space ships and all the great things that come with it.</p>

<p>If Notch taught a bunch of kids about circuits and logic gates in Minecraft, he aims to teach them about programming in assembly as each ship contains a simulated 16-bit CPU. Here&rsquo;s <a href="http://0x10c.com/doc/dcpu-16.txt">a spec</a> for the simulated CPU.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Minecraft Catsplosion]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.nickoneill.name/a-minecraft-catsplosion/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-01T17:01:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.nickoneill.name/a-minecraft-catsplosion</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A (melon) slice of what makes Minecraft great. It&apos;s just a bunch of objects connected by a bag of rules, some of which you can exploit to make an infinite fountain of cats.</p>

<div class="video-container">
    <iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://blog.nickoneill.name//www.youtube.com/embed/iNw2YcAK9Wc" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
