<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: movies | authenticgeek]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.nickoneill.name/categories/movies/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.nickoneill.name/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-28T12:26:49-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.nickoneill.name/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick O'Neill]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ender&apos;s Game Full Cast and Crew]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.nickoneill.name/enders-game-full-cast-and-crew/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-15T19:42:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.nickoneill.name/enders-game-full-cast-and-crew</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The cast list is out for 2013s -biggest disappointment- best movie, the film interpretation of Ender&apos;s Game. And get this: <em>Harrison Ford</em> as <em>Graff</em>.</p>

<p>Otherwise mostly unknowns since it features a bunch of kids. That kid from <em>Hugo</em> as Ender is spot on, otherwise no one is really as I pictured them. Or I simply never had a very good idea of what anyone looked like.</p>

<p>Also, the headshots that kids do for acting are fucking creepy.</p>

<br /><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1731141/fullcredits">source</a>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[In Time]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.nickoneill.name/In+TIme/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-13T11:39:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.nickoneill.name/In TIme</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1637688/">In Time</a> turned out to be a movie that relied far too heavily on making time puns. As for the plot, there are about a million ways one can make an interesting scifi storyline with immortality <em>and</em> time-as-currency but the writer/director managed to keep everything pretty shallow.</p>

<p>Speaking of, writing <em>and</em> directing a film seems like a Lucas-esque control freak move. You&rsquo;re the best writer you could convince to do your movie? Unlikely. And the best director? These odds are not getting better. Don&rsquo;t even get me started on people who write/direct/star.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m a fan of Matt Bomer on <em>White Collar</em> so I was disappointed by his lack of screen time. He may have been the only character in the entire film with clear motivations, though that may have been simply a side effect of being a chracter who dies early.</p>

<p>In conclusion, do not watch.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
