<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: booze | authenticgeek]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.nickoneill.name/categories/booze/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.nickoneill.name/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-20T14:43:43-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.nickoneill.name/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick O'Neill]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[White House Beer Recipes]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.nickoneill.name/beer-recipes-white-house/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-04T13:30:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.nickoneill.name/beer-recipes-white-house</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been brewing beer at home since the spring so it was pretty cool to see the White House staff getting into brewing and then releasing their own <a href="http://www.whitehouse.gov/blog/2012/09/01/ale-chief-white-house-beer-recipe">recipes for Honey Ale and Honey Porter</a>.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m tempted to pick up the ingredients for the porter and try it out &ndash; I&rsquo;m sure the <a href="http://www.sanfranciscobrewcraft.com/">Brewcraft store in SF</a> (where I get all my recipes) is getting plenty of requests for those ingredients. So far I&rsquo;ve made a Pale Ale (decent!), an Amber Ale (slightly watery), a Pilsner (tasty but slightly overcarbonated) and an IPA is almost ready to be bottled.</p>

<p>Echoing Sam Kass (White House assistant chef), it&rsquo;s surprisingly easy to make a really tasty beer at home. I would suggest two things if you&rsquo;re new to brewing: get the supplies to do primary and secondary fermentation and pay attention to your sanitization. Transfering to a second container after a few days will get your beer off the dead yeast which can give off weird flavors (there are simple brewing methods that use a single container for all fermentation before the bottle). Keeping equipment sanitized through the entire process is not hard but you have to pay attention to what tools are in a clean state and only use those on your clean equipment (or resanitize them). Wild yeasts and bacteria are everywhere and a batch of fermenting beer can be a pretty ideal place for unpleasant things to grow.</p>

<p>Go forth and brew White House beer!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Go-powered Beer at Original Gravity Pub]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.nickoneill.name/original-gravity-pub/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-15T13:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.nickoneill.name/original-gravity-pub</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last month saw the official opening of San Jose&rsquo;s newest drinking establishment, <a href="http://www.originalgravitypub.com/">Original Gravity Public House</a>. Dan is a friend from before he became a full-time beer slinger and I offered to whip up something for the website a while back.</p>

<p>As a craft beer bar they had the opportunity to change their selection of beers regularly and wanted a way to reflect those changes on their website and in the bar with minimal effort. You can see the virtual result on their website which has an up-to-date list of all their current beers. The other solution was showing a list of all their current beers on a 40" TV above the bar, you can see a picture of how it turned out here:</p>

<p><span class="blogimage">
<img src="http://blog.nickoneill.name/images/ogtv.jpg" alt="Original Gravity Beer List" /><br />
From <a href="http://www.yelp.com/biz_photos/uXCsgEdownjTGlQtnWvkjQ?select=Gxg_cJOzDkKUv8pnprOiBQ#Gxg_cJOzDkKUv8pnprOiBQ">Yelp</a>
</span></p>

<p>Designing for a big screen TV is not something I remember doing since webTV stopped being <em>a thing</em>. It was a fun exercise in scaling and clarity, and it seems like it has been successful so far.</p>

<p>The behind-the-scenes wiring is pretty minimal. I built a small Go-powered web service that allows Dan to add to, remove from and reorder the beer list which is written to disk. Whenever an item changes, templates are built and put in their proper locations. Static publishing at its best.</p>

<p>The bar view on the TV is just a fullscreen view of a special website in Chrome, it periodically refreshes to pick up the updated beer list. Nothing is particularly complex about the system, just adding together all the right components. I&rsquo;ve been spending more time writing servers and other tools in Go so this was a good way to learn more of the standard library. As far as I know this is the first Go-powered craft beer bar, though I haven&rsquo;t spent a lot of time asking around at bars.</p>

<p>Dan and friends at Original Gravity have a really welcoming space and some very tasty beers on tap. Stop by if you need a drink in San Jose!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Industry City Distillery]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.nickoneill.name/industry-city-distillery/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-06T11:42:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.nickoneill.name/industry-city-distillery</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love the philosophies behind Industry City Distillery, shown in <a href="http://vimeo.com/42991839">this very well produced video</a>.</p>

<p>The first thing that grabs me is the attention to detail in each of the processes shown. Not only are they paying incredible attention to the science of distilling but the labeling is done on an old letterpress which gives it that extra ounce of style.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thecityfoundry.com/">The City Foundry</a>, the larger organization around the distillery, has similarly awesome goals. It&rsquo;s easy to say that manufacturing is entirely dead in the water but TCF is based on the idea that it simply needs to evolve into a product that fits the future.</p>

<p>Their todo list is equally ambitious:</p>

<blockquote><ul>
<li>Secure and outfit a 6000 SQFT manufacturing facility</li>
<li>Create a highly advanced distillation process</li>
<li>Develop a small alcohol fueled turbine engine</li>
<li>Find and purchase a derelict power station</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>I love it, there are so many great ideas here.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
