<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ideals | authenticgeek]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.nickoneill.name/categories/ideals/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.nickoneill.name/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-16T12:32:46-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.nickoneill.name/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nick O'Neill]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Industry City Distillery]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.nickoneill.name/industry-city-distillery/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-06T11:42:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.nickoneill.name/industry-city-distillery</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love the philosophies behind Industry City Distillery, shown in <a href="http://vimeo.com/42991839">this very well produced video</a>.</p>

<p>The first thing that grabs me is the attention to detail in each of the processes shown. Not only are they paying incredible attention to the science of distilling but the labeling is done on an old letterpress which gives it that extra ounce of style.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.thecityfoundry.com/">The City Foundry</a>, the larger organization around the distillery, has similarly awesome goals. It&rsquo;s easy to say that manufacturing is entirely dead in the water but TCF is based on the idea that it simply needs to evolve into a product that fits the future.</p>

<p>Their todo list is equally ambitious:</p>

<blockquote><ul>
<li>Secure and outfit a 6000 SQFT manufacturing facility</li>
<li>Create a highly advanced distillation process</li>
<li>Develop a small alcohol fueled turbine engine</li>
<li>Find and purchase a derelict power station</li>
</ul>
</blockquote>

<p>I love it, there are so many great ideas here.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Valve Handbook]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.nickoneill.name/the-valve-handbook/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-21T17:10:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.nickoneill.name/the-valve-handbook</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I don&rsquo;t often recommend reading company handbooks but the <a href="http://cdn.flamehaus.com/Valve_Handbook_LowRes.pdf">Valve company handbook</a> is definitely an exception.</p>

<p>It feels like a bunch of smart nerds got together and ignored all the management advice they were given from every other boilerplate company. Then they made a bunch of awesome games and didn&rsquo;t compromise on their values. Now they&rsquo;re smart rich nerds.</p>

<p>via <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/rr/status/193741110558990336">@rr</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
